<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>BitsMakeMeCrazy | Kushal Vyas's Blog</title><link href="http://kushalvyas.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://kushalvyas.github.io/feeds/object-recognition-classification-cv.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://kushalvyas.github.io/</id><updated>2016-07-13T20:40:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Bag of Visual Words</title><link href="http://kushalvyas.github.io/BOV.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-07-13T20:40:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Kushal Vyas</name></author><id>tag:kushalvyas.github.io,2016-07-13:BOV.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bag of Visual Words is an extention to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NLP&lt;/span&gt; algorithm Bag of Words used for image classification. It is far most widely used apart from using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s. I may not know much about pristine knowledge about machine learning but I can tell for sure that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BOVW&lt;/span&gt; is one of the finest things I&amp;#8217;ve encountered in my study till&amp;nbsp;now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets begin with a few introductory concepts required Bag of words. First is&amp;nbsp;, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clustering : Lets say there is a bunch of Wrigleys Skittles (confectionary). And someone is to tell you to group them according to their color. It&amp;#8217;s quite simple .. aint it! Simply seperate all red, blue, green, etc in different parts of the room. Here, we differentiated and seperated them on basis of &lt;strong&gt;color only&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
So moving on to a more complex situation that would give a much profound meaning to clustering. Suppose there is a room full of utilities, be it accesories, clothing, utensils, electronics, etc. Now, if someone is told to seperate out into well formed groups of similar items, one would essentially be performing&amp;nbsp;clustering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, clustering can be said as the grouping a set of objects in such a way that objects in the same group are much similar, than to those in other&amp;nbsp;groups/sets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on, lets&amp;#8217; decide as to how we perform clustering. The selection of clustering algorithm depends more on what kind of similarity model is to be chosen. There are cases wherein, the plain&amp;#8217;ol clustering impression that everyone so simply elucidates may not be the right choice. For example, there exists various models, such as centroid oriented - Kmeans, or Distribution based models - that involve clustering for statistical data; such places require Density based clustering (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DBSCAN&lt;/span&gt;) ,&amp;nbsp;etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PROGRESS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ObjectRecognition"></category></entry></feed>